J SARATH KUMAR

- 冷:BANGALORE, KA, 560016 圓 8498906002 💹 :sarathkumarj800123@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sarath-kumar-j GitHub: github.com/Sarath-Kumar-J-800123

SUMMARY

Frontend and Backend developer with 1 years of experience. Intend to build a career with leading corporate of Hi-tech environment with committed & dedicated people, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential. I desire to work as a key player and team member in challenging & creative environment

WORK EXPERIENCE

Java Full Stack Developer, PalleTechnologies

Feb 2023 - Present

Bangalore

Collaborated on the design, development, and deployment of web applications.

Contributed to front-end development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript frameworks.

Assisted in back-end development with Java, Spring, and RESTful APIs.

Conducted testing, bug fixing, and participated in code reviews.

Demonstrated proactive problem-solving and a commitment to continuous learning.

Feb 2020 - Jan 2023 Hvderabad

Instrumentation engineers design, develop, install and maintain equipment to monitor and control machinery.

They configure automated processes to improve the productivity, reliability and safety of production.

They might build instruments like: Dynamometers for measuring torque.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Instrumentation

June 2017- July 2019

Tirupati

Sri Venkateswara University

Control systems for outdoor equipment. System modules for automation technology. Sensor technology and optoelectronics (e.g. control and alarm devices)

Bachelor of Science in Maths, Physics and Electrons

July 2014 - April 2017

P V K N Govt College

Chittoor

power, communication, control, signal processing, embedded systems, robotics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

· Technologies: JDBC, SERVLETS, JSP, J2EE, Object Oriented Programming, Node JS, React JS

· Framework: Hibernate , Spring , Spring MVC , Spring Boot

· Databases: MySQL

· Interest: Coding, Night Rides

PROJECTS

Human Resource Management System

- **Java:** The core programming language for developing the application logic and user interface.
- · JDBC: The Java API for connecting and interacting with the database.
- **Relational Database Management System:** MySQL, PostgreSQL, or any other RDBMS for storing student-related data.
- **HTML, CSS and JavaScript:** For web-based components or web integration, if required.

Ticket Booking System Sign Up

- Implemented secure user authentication and registration functionalities to ensure data privacy and access control.
- Developed an intuitive registration form allowing users to input essential details such as name, email, password and contact information.
- Utilized JDBC to establish a connection with the backend database, storing newly registered user information securely.
- Leveraged JSP to dynamically generate content, enhancing the overall registration experience.